<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?><w:document mc:Ignorable="w14 w15 wp14" xmlns:wpc="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordprocessingCanvas" xmlns:mc="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/markup-compatibility/2006" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:r="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/relationships" xmlns:m="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/math" xmlns:v="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:vml" xmlns:wp14="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordprocessingDrawing" xmlns:wp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/drawingml/2006/wordprocessingDrawing" xmlns:w10="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:word" xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main" xmlns:w14="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordml" xmlns:w15="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2012/wordml" xmlns:wpg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordprocessingGroup" xmlns:wpi="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordprocessingInk" xmlns:wne="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2006/wordml" xmlns:wps="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordprocessingShape" xmlns:cx="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/drawing/2014/chartex" xmlns:cx1="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/drawing/2015/9/8/chartex" xmlns:cx2="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/drawing/2015/10/21/chartex" xmlns:cx3="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/drawing/2016/5/9/chartex" xmlns:cx4="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/drawing/2016/5/10/chartex" xmlns:cx5="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/drawing/2016/5/11/chartex" xmlns:cx6="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/drawing/2016/5/12/chartex" xmlns:cx7="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/drawing/2016/5/13/chartex" xmlns:cx8="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/drawing/2016/5/14/chartex" xmlns:aink="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/drawing/2016/ink" xmlns:am3d="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/drawing/2017/model3d" xmlns:w16cex="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2018/wordml/cex" xmlns:w16cid="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2016/wordml/cid" xmlns:w16="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2018/wordml" xmlns:w16sdtdh="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2020/wordml/sdtdatahash" xmlns:w16se="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2015/wordml/symex"><w:body><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/><w:spacing w:before="240" w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">CONTACT INFORMATION</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">David Kaniaru Kamau | Curriculum Vitae</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">dkamale@gmail.com</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">254-723-7277</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/><w:spacing w:before="240" w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">PERSONAL PROFILE</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">Experienced IT professional with 16 years of expertise in deploying and managing both on-premises and cloud infrastructure. Skilled in application support and cybersecurity, consistently enhancing customer satisfaction through customized technical solutions. Proven leader in the operation, maintenance, and support of advanced systems.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">KEY SKILLS:</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">IT Leadership, CX, Service Delivery, Internet Service Provider Experience, SD WAN, IT infrastructure &amp; Ops, Technical Support, IP Networks, Storage, Virtualization (VMware &amp; HyperV), Cloud Computing (AWS, Azure), IT Security, End User Training, Vendor Management, IT Procurement, Budgeting, Project Management, IT Policy Formulation, Big Data, Python programming., WORK EXPERIENCEHead of Client Service &amp; Projects - Echotel International 				               Jan 2024 - Present, Responsible for the running and management of the Client Service and Projects Departments, comprising three Project Managers and 17 Technical Support and Enterprise Engineers, providing project implementation and support to clients and partners across Sub-Saharan Africa.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/><w:spacing w:before="240" w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">ACHIEVEMENTS</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">Successfully led the deployment and commissioning of an Omnichannel customer service platform across Sub-Saharan Africa, resulting in enhanced customer engagement and improved Net Promoter and Customer Satisfaction scores. Standardized Customer Experience (CX) strategies to strengthen CX governance across eight African country offices. Developed and implemented a comprehensive vendor management framework for multinational operations in the region. Established a Global Service Desk, streamlining operations across Sub-Saharan Africa. Designed a customer experience portal focused on automating customer journey maps, significantly enhancing efficiency. Automated monitoring systems to deliver outage notifications to vendors, clients, and support agents, reducing manual intervention by 30%. Deployed a Starlink ground station for satellite monitoring. Implemented SD-WAN solutions using FortiGate and Meraki for 76 KFC locations in Kenya and Uganda. Currently overseeing client migration from Avanti Hylas 2 to the Hylas 4 satellite platform across Sub-Saharan Africa. As IT Support Supervisor at Church World Service (CWS Africa) from January 2023 to December 2024, coordinated IT support for cloud and on-premises resources at the Nairobi office and across 42 field sites, ensuring project execution and SLA compliance for all service requests.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/><w:spacing w:before="240" w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">ACHIEVEMENTS</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">Led the successful construction and launch of the CWS Uganda data center, overseeing all aspects of computing systems, storage, HVAC, power, access control, and inter-connectivity, ensuring timely and budget-compliant completion. As a Solutions Architect, facilitated the integration of CWS/RSCs with the US Government Refugee database using Okta on AWS. Executed a Paper Lite processing system, achieving an annual cost reduction of $16,000 by managing the RFQ process for E-signature pads, overseeing their installation and configuration, and conducting user training. Established internet connectivity for six field processing sites in Ethiopia and developed the IT function for CWS Uganda, recruiting and training two IT specialists. Served as the IT Point of Contact for the NIST audit for CWS/RSC Uganda, receiving commendation from the Country Director. Delivered IT support across multiple African nations including Namibia, Chad, Niger, Ethiopia, Burundi, and Uganda. Enhanced IT support efficiency by implementing project tracking boards on Monday.com and training a team of 15 IT Support Specialists. As IT Infrastructure &amp; Support Manager at African Banking Corporation from August 2013 to November 2020, provided strategic oversight for enterprise-level infrastructure and end-user support, aligning IT initiatives with industry trends to improve service efficiency and effectiveness.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/><w:spacing w:before="240" w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">ACHIEVEMENTS</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">Successfully led a comprehensive hardware refresh of the bank&apos;s data center, including upgrades to switching, routing, firewall, and storage infrastructure, which enhanced operational efficiency and reduced response times. Spearheaded the upgrade of network cabling and switching fabric at the bank&apos;s headquarters and 12 branches, significantly improving infrastructure performance. Played a key role in establishing the bank&apos;s disaster recovery site, achieving cost savings of $8,000. Transitioned 450 users from Microsoft Exchange to Google Workspace, elevating email system availability to 99.99%. Achieved a Customer Satisfaction (CSAT) rating of 96% by optimizing Helpdesk support processes. Implemented advanced security measures using McAfee EPO, Web Application Firewall, SIEM, and Next Generation Firewalls, resulting in reduced security incidents. Enhanced monitoring systems for network and server infrastructure, improving Estimated Time to Restore (ETR) by 20%. Increased WAN and internet uptime from 93% to 99% through managed WAN services and reduced annual connectivity costs by $20,000 through strategic outsourcing. Conducted a comprehensive skill-gap analysis for the IT team, providing a detailed report on training requirements and associated costs.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/><w:spacing w:before="240" w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">ACHIEVEMENTS</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">Achieved an exceptional 99% infrastructure availability during the 2013 pre-election and election periods for the BVR exercise, playing a pivotal role in ensuring operational stability. Additionally, functioned as IT Trainer and Cisco Partner Relationship Administrator at Access Kenya, Nairobi.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">MAY 2008 - MAY 2011</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">Spearheaded the technology training division alongside HR, effectively launching and executing comprehensive blended learning programs focusing on Cisco solutions.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/><w:spacing w:before="240" w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">ACHIEVEMENTS</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">Played a key role in establishing and equipping Access Kenya&apos;s training function and center, collaborating closely with the HR department. Facilitated the company&apos;s advancement to Cisco Premier Partner status, achieving procurement cost savings of up to 40% on Cisco products and services. Successfully trained 100 colleagues across Sales, Marketing, and Technical teams in Cisco solutions. Served as Technical Support Engineer and IT Trainer at Computer Learning Centre &amp; Mart Networks in Nairobi.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">JANUARY 2005 - MAY 2008</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">Provided expert on-site and remote technical support to end-users, while also fulfilling the role of IT trainer. Delivered instructor-led training sessions on certifications including ICDL, A+, N+, CCNA, and CCNP for both internal staff and external clients.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/><w:spacing w:before="240" w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">ACHIEVEMENTS</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">Recognized as &apos;Best Cisco Trainer&apos; in 2007 and 2008 for successfully training over 2,000 professionals over three years.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/><w:spacing w:before="240" w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">EDUCATION</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">2022 - 2025</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">Master of Science Degree in Big Data Technologies - University of East London</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">2002 - 2005</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">British Technical Educational Council (BTEC) EDEXCEL, Higher National Diploma in Computing - Computer Learning Centre.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/><w:spacing w:before="240" w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAINING</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">Currently pursuing AWS Certified Solutions Architect Professional. Certifications include: AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals, ITIL Foundation, Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA), Cisco Certified Network Professional (CCNP), Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA), Cisco Certified Design Associate (CCDA), and Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA). Additional skills in user support, network support, Siemon Distributed Listed Installer (DLI), customer service, project management, and public speaking.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/><w:spacing w:before="240" w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">ADDITIONAL INFORMATION</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">Dedicated technology enthusiast with a strong track record in driving innovation. Possess a passion for cultural exploration through travel, and excel in crafting compelling narratives. Skilled public speaker capable of inspiring and influencing diverse audiences.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/><w:spacing w:before="240" w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">REFEREES</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:spacing w:after="120"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t xml:space="preserve">References will be provided upon request to support my qualifications and accomplishments.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:sectPr><w:pgSz w:w="11906" w:h="16838" w:orient="portrait"/><w:pgMar w:top="720" w:right="720" w:bottom="720" w:left="720" w:header="708" w:footer="708" w:gutter="0"/><w:pgNumType/><w:docGrid w:linePitch="360"/></w:sectPr></w:body></w:document>
